getaround.com 2019-11-15

# Privacy Policy

Getaround, Inc. ("we" or "Getaround") is committed to protecting your privacy and informing you about how your information is used. This Privacy Policy explains our practices regarding the collection, use, disclosure, and protection of information that is collected through our website, mobile application, and any other mobile or online service owned and offered by Getaround (our “Service”). Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given to them in our Terms of Service.

### Personal Information We Collect From You

We collect personal information from you in order to provide our Service and offer you a personalized, useful, and efficient experience. The categories of personal information we collect can include:

#### Identifying Information

You provide us information about yourself, such as your name, age, address, email address, university or other affiliation, and password, when you register for a Member account with the Service. We also collect a copy of your driver’s license and billing and payment information if you utilize our Service. If you correspond with us by email, we may retain the content of your email messages, your email address, and our responses. We may also retain any messages you send through the Service. You may provide us information in User Content you post to the Service.

#### Payment Information

Getaround collects your personal payment information, including information stored on outside services that you may use with Getaround, such as PayPal. By submitting your payment information and/or linking your Getaround account with an outside payment service such as PayPal, you authorize Getaround to access and use this information in order to provide you with and accept payment for the Service. This allows us to both confirm your identity and provide you with seamless, hassle-free transactions. You can check the current fees, fines, and penalties applicable to use of our Service in our Fee and Commission Schedule.

#### Driver's Record

We check your driver's record to make sure you and your car meet Getaround safety standards. By registering with Getaround, you authorize us to access your driver's record from state DMVs, RMVs, and other applicable entities, and this authorization extends to Getaround throughout the entire time you use our Service, so that Getaround may re-check your records from time to time. You also authorize said entities to release this information to Getaround.

#### Vehicle History and Inspection

If you own a vehicle that is used on Getaround, we will inspect the vehicle, collect information identifying the vehicle (like a license plate number, VIN), and obtain a vehicle history report to make sure the vehicle is safe for you and other drivers to use. By registering with Getaround, you authorize us to obtain this information, and you authorize applicable entities such as DMVs, RMVs, inspection companies, and auto mechanics to release such information to Getaround.

#### Social Media

When you interact with our Service through various social media, such as when you log in through Facebook or when you like or post a comment to our Facebook page or interact with us on other social media, we may receive information from the social network, such as your profile information, profile picture, user name, user ID associated with your social media account, age range, language, country, friends list, and any other information you permit the social network to share with third parties. The data we receive is dependent upon your privacy settings with the social network. You should always review, and, if necessary, adjust your privacy settings on third-party websites and services before linking or connecting them to Getaround’s Service.

We use personal information to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of the Service, as well as to communicate directly with you, such as to send you email messages and push notifications, and permit you to communicate with others on the Service or on social media or invite others to join the Service.  We may also use information to provide personalized content, including advertising.  We may also send you Service-related emails or messages (e.g., account verification, change or updates to features of the Service, technical and security notices).  For more information about your communication preferences, see Your Choices Regarding Your Information below.

### Usage Information We Collect

#### Data Gathered from In-Vehicle Hardware

The Getaround Connect™ installed in each Getaround car allows us to gather information about your vehicle use, including time of use, location and movements, speed of travel, distance traveled, and other aspects of your vehicle use. We use this information to (i) provide you with the Service, (ii) understand your driving and use habits over time and potentially provide you with related benefits, such as better insurance rates or other perks for safe driving, (iii) record vehicle movements and driver behavior in case of an accident or theft, and (iv) aggregate your data with other drivers' data and better understand how people use our Service and how we can make it even better for you in the future. We may share this information with third parties as described below.

#### Location Tracking

The location of all Getaround cars you use is tracked by GPS (or equivalent), cellular, WiFi, Bluetooth, or similar technologies. Location information is tracked both on your Getaround-enabled smart phone and by the vehicle's Getaround Connect **™**. Location information is shared in limited ways. As a car Owner, you can control when and where other Getaround Users can see the location of your car while parked. If you are renting a car, the Owner of the car will be able to see the location of the rented car and will be able to see the car’s location and movements in real time. 

We monitor the location of all cars to provide our Service, to prevent theft, and to allow us to locate you in case of accident, emergency, lock-out, etc. We may maintain location data in order to aggregate trends and metrics and may share de-identified and/or aggregate location and movement data with third parties for advertising, research, analytics, and other purposes.  We may share location information in some instances as described below.

#### Third Party Hardware Devices

As a Renter, you acknowledge and understand that dashboard cameras, mileage and location tracking devices, and other similar devices may be installed in the cars listed on Getaround. You further acknowledge and understand that any such device installed in an Owner’s car is installed at the Owner’s sole discretion, without direction from Getaround, and that Getaround makes no warranties or representations regarding the conformity of such devices to any laws applicable to their usage or installation. Any concerns about the presence, operation, functionality, and data storage of these devices must be addressed directly with the Owner who has installed them. Getaround does not collect or store any data generated by such hardware.

#### Use of Cookies and Other Technology to Collect Information

When you visit our website or use our mobile app or Service, we and our business partners may collect certain information about your computer or device through technology such as cookies, web beacons, log files, or other tracking/recording tools. The information we collect through the use of tracking technologies includes but is not limited to IP address, browser information, referring/exit pages and URLs, click stream data and information about how you interact with links on the website, mobile app, or Service, domain names, landing pages, page views, and cookie data that allows us to uniquely identify your browser and track your browsing behavior on our site. We may also use clear gifs or other technology in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened and which links are clicked by recipients. Some or all of this data may be combined with other personally identifying information described above. We may also collect analytics data, or use third-party analytics tools, to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Service and to understand more about the demographics of our users.  These tools collect information sent by your browser or mobile device, including the pages you visit, your use of third party applications, and other information that assists us in analyzing and improving the Service. We may work with third parties to employ technologies, including the application of statistical modeling tools, which attempt to recognize you across multiple devices. Although we do our best to honor the privacy preferences of our visitors, we are not able to respond to Do Not Track signals from your browser at this time.

When you access our Service by or through a mobile device, we may receive or collect and store a unique identification number associated with your device or our mobile application (including, for example, a UDID, Unique ID for Advertisers (“IDFA”), Google Ad ID, or Windows Advertising ID or other identifier), mobile carrier, device type, model and manufacturer, mobile device operating system brand and model, phone number, and, depending on your mobile device settings, your geographical location data, including GPS coordinates (e.g. latitude and/or longitude), WiFi location, or similar information regarding the location of your mobile device. 

We use or may use the data collected through these technologies to: (i) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit; (ii) provide custom, personalized content and information, including advertising; (iii) identify you across multiple devices; (iv) provide and monitor the effectiveness of our Service; (v) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, usage, and demographic patterns on our website and our Service; (vi) diagnose or fix technology problems; and (vii) otherwise to plan for and enhance our service.

#### Calls and text messages

We enable users to call or text each other through the Service. For example, we enable owners and renters to call or text each other without disclosing their telephone numbers. To provide this functionality, Getaround and our third-party service provider receive some information regarding the calls or texts, including the date and time of the call or text, and the content of the text messages. We may also use this information for customer support services (including to resolve disputes between users), for safety and security purposes, and to improve the Service.

#### Carrier Consent

You authorize your wireless operator (AT&T, Sprint, T-Mobile, US Cellular, Verizon, or any other branded wireless operator) to disclose to the Getaround and its third-party service providers your mobile number, name, address, email, network status, customer type, customer role, billing type, mobile device identifiers (IMSI and IMEI) and other subscriber status and device details, if available, solely to verify your identity and prevent fraud for the duration of your use of the Services. **‍**

#### Telephone Consumer Protection Act (TCPA) Consent

Notwithstanding any current or prior election to opt in or opt out of receiving calls or SMS messages (including text messages) from us, our agents, representatives, affiliates, or anyone calling on our behalf, you expressly consent to be contacted by us, our agents, representatives, affiliates, or anyone calling on our behalf for any and all purposes arising out of or relating to your Service, at any telephone number, or physical or electronic address you provide or at which you may be reached. You agree that we may contact you in any way, including SMS messages or text messages, calls using prerecorded messages or artificial voice, and calls and messages delivered using auto telephone dialing system or an automatic texting system. Automated messages may be played when the telephone is answered, whether by you or someone else. In the event that an agent or representative calls, he or she may also leave a message on your answering machine, voice mail, or send one via text.

You consent to receive SMS messages (including text messages), calls and messages (including prerecorded and artificial voice and autodialed) from us, our agents, representatives, affiliates or anyone calling on our behalf at the specific number(s) you have provided to us, or numbers we can reasonably associate with your account (through skip trace, caller ID capture or other means), with information or questions about your use of the Service. You certify, warrant and represent that the telephone numbers that you have provided to us are your contact numbers. You represent that you are permitted to receive calls at each of the telephone numbers you have provided to us. You agree to promptly alert us whenever you stop using a particular telephone number.

Your cellular or mobile telephone provider will charge you according to the type of plan you carry. You also agree that we may contact you by email, using any email address you have provided to us or that you provide to us in the future.

We may listen to and/or record phone calls between you and our representatives without notice to you as permitted by applicable law. For example, we listen to and record calls for training and quality monitoring purposes.  

### How We Share Your Information

We may share your personal information in the instances described below.  For further information on your choices regarding your information, see Your Choices Regarding Your Information below.

Getaround may share your personally identifiable information with third party vendors, consultants or other service providers that perform services on our behalf or otherwise help provide the Service to you, under reasonable confidentiality terms.

We may share your information in connection with any company transaction, such as a merger, sale of all or a portion of company assets or shares, reorganization, financing, change of control or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company or third party. or in the event of bankruptcy or related or similar proceedings.

We may share your personal information with others with whom you communicate on the Service and any information that you post or share publicly on our website or service. Any personal information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Service, such as User Content, becomes available to the public, as controlled by any applicable privacy settings. If you remove information that you posted to the Service, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Service, or if other Users have copied or saved that information.

Other brands owned or controlled by Getaround, and other companies owned by or under common ownership as Getaround, which also includes our subsidiaries (i.e., any organization we own or control) or our ultimate holding company (i.e., any organization that owns or controls us) and any subsidiaries it owns.  These companies will use your personal information in the same way as we can under this Policy.

We may share license plate information with governmental agencies to ensure compliance with local parking rules and restrictions, to respond or settle a citation issued during a trip, or in accordance with a parking program or partnership operated with a governmental agency.

We may also disclose personal information if we believe it to be reasonably necessary to (i) satisfy any applicable law or regulation and comply with legal process, such as search warrant, subpoena or court order, or other government request served on us or on our affiliates; (ii) to enforce our Terms of Service, including to investigate potential violations thereof; (iii) take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations, or to protect the security or integrity of our site; and (iv) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Getaround, our Users, or others. Typically, our policy is not to share personal information and location data with governmental agencies, except as pursuant to a search warrant, subpoena, court order, or as otherwise compelled to do so by legal process, though there may be circumstances in which we may disclose such information without such legal process if we reasonably believe such disclosure is necessary to protect the health and safety of an individual, prevent or mitigate the harm of crime or illegal activity, or other compelling circumstance. We will use our best effort to provide you notice of a law enforcement request for your personal information before we release such information, unless we are not permitted to do so. 

#### Sharing of Your Information with Business Partners; Expanded Service

We may use information about you in partnership with outside companies in the course of providing you with additional services related to Getaround, such as ride-sharing or parking benefits. When you purchase, register, or otherwise express interest in a product or service offered by a third party through Getaround or sponsored on our site, you consent to our sharing of your personal information with those parties. When you choose to participate in rewards programs, contests, discount offers, or other programs that involve third parties, you authorize Getaround to share your personal information with those parties, who may use such information in accordance with their own privacy policies.  In these cases we will only share the information reasonably needed to provide you with service. Information that is shared with third parties is subject to the privacy policies of those parties, which may differ from Getaround's privacy policies. 

#### Sharing and Using Aggregate or Anonymized Information

We may aggregate, anonymize, or otherwise strip data of all personally identifying characteristics and may share that anonymized and/or aggregated data with third parties, in a manner that cannot reasonably identify any individual.  For example, we may share de-identified location data and location history with third parties that analyze location and movement trends, and we may share information that would identify a particular  as well as the driving history, and general demographics of the drivers (i.e., gender and age bracket) of that car in order to analyze, develop and improve our partner programs.

### Your Choices About Your Information

#### Profile and Data Sharing Settings

You can change your account information and preferences at any time by logging onto your account.

#### Communications 

We will not sell your contact information to third parties for marketing purposes. 

We may communicate with you via in-app notifications, email, SMS text, or other method. You control when and how (e.g. email, SMS, etc.) you would like to receive messages, and you may be able to opt-out of receiving certain types of messages.  

We may send you notifications of activity on the Service to the email address you give us, in accordance with any applicable privacy settings. For instance, if you are a car Owner, we will send you information about your car's rental status. You can turn these notifications off or modify how often and in what form you receive them.

Getaround may send you other messages in the course of operation of our Service, such as notifications from other Users, updates about Service changes and new features, and important news that may impact your use and enjoyment of Getaround. These communications may contain banners, ads, or promotional material provided by third parties. If you click on the third party link, you will be taken to that service, and your information will thereafter be subject to that party’s privacy policy.  You may be able to opt-out of receiving promotional emails by clicking the “unsubscribe” button at the footer of promotional email communications. Note that you are not permitted to unsubscribe or opt-out of non-promotional messages regarding your account.

By providing Getaround your email address, you consent to our using the email address to send you Service-related notices, including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail.

#### Third Party Tracking and Advertising 

We may share, or we may permit third party ad networks, social media companies, and other third party services to collect information about the browsing behavior of our users of Service through cookies, social plug-ins, or other tracking technology. We may permit third party online advertising networks to collect information about your use of our Service over time, including location information, so that they may play or display ads that may be relevant to your interests on our Service as well as on other websites or services, or on other devices you may use. Typically, the information is collected through cookies or similar tracking technologies. You may be able to “opt out” of the collection of information through cookies or other tracking technology by actively managing the settings on your browser or mobile device. Please refer to your browser’s or mobile device’s technical information for instructions on how to delete, disable, and/or limit the use of cookies or other tracking/recording tools. Depending on your mobile device, you may not be able to control all tracking technologies through your device settings.  You may also be able to limit interest-based advertising through the settings on your browser or device. For example, you may be able to opt-out of some interest-based advertising on your mobile device by selecting “limit ad tracking” (iOS) or “opt-out of interest based ads” (Android). To learn more about interest-based advertising and how you may opt-out of some of this tracking, you may wish to visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s online resources, at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices> and/or the DAA’s resources at [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices).  You may also be able to opt-out of some – but not all – interest-based ads served by mobile ad networks by visiting  <http://youradchoices.com/appchoices> and downloading the mobile AppChoices app.  If you have any questions about third party tracking and advertising, you can contact us directly at help@getaround.com.

#### Data Retention

Following termination or deactivation of your Member account, Getaround may retain your information for a commercially reasonable time for backup, archival, or audit purposes, or to maintain and improve the Service -- for instance, for the safety of other Users, we may need access to information about cars you have used in case one of those cars is in an accident. We may maintain location information and other usage data for record-keeping and analytics purposes. Furthermore, Getaround may retain and continue to use indefinitely all information (including User Content) contained in your communications to other Users or posted to public or semi-public areas of the Service after termination or deactivation of your Member account. Please contact us at help@getaround.com if you wish to delete your account information from our systems, though we may not be able to delete all information, as noted in this Privacy Policy.

## How We Protect Your Information

Getaround cares about the security of your information and uses commercially reasonable physical, administrative, and technological safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of all information we collect and that we share with our service providers.  However, no security system is impenetrable, and we cannot guarantee the security of our systems 100%.  In the event that any information under our control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, we will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation and, where appropriate, notify those individuals whose information may have been compromised and take other steps, in accordance with any applicable laws and regulations. To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information and for controlling access to your email communications from Getaround, at all times.

#### Children's Privacy  

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, Getaround does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register as Members. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us [here](https://help.getaround.com/hc/en-us/requests/new).

#### Links to Other Websites

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from the Service, nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including those that have a link on our website, is subject to that website's own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

#### Notification Procedures

It is our policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to you via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on the Service, as determined by Getaround in its sole discretion. We reserve the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to you, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification, as described in this Privacy Policy.

#### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on the Service to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

For any questions on this privacy policy, please contact us by submitting a support request [here](https://help.getaround.com/hc/en-us/requests/new) or by postal mail at Getaround, Inc., 55 Green Street, San Francisco, CA 94111.
